And how long have you lived in Ukraine? I'm almost three.
А сколько ты жил в Украине Я предела три 3,
You were there for three years and you
по лет там был ты три года и ты
speak Ukrainian normally.
нормально говоришь на украинском языке
Well, it's very, very normal to me, but I
прям мне очень очень нормально но я все
still understand and speak a little.
одно понимаю и говорю немного
Hello Hello,
Здравствуй Здравствуйте вы
where am I from Turkey?
Откуда я из Турции Турция
What do you write in Germany? Germany
что у вас пишет Германия сейчас
? And I am from Israel.
о А я из Израиля сейчас в
people,
говорил Ну да это политики а людей
there are no problems with Israel, I am in the I
нет проблем с израилем я в при Я курд
don't know Kurds, you know, but I know the Kurds, yes, the
не знаю ты знаешь а курды знаю да
Kurdistan Workers' Party, I know the Kurds, the
Рабочая партия курдистана знаю курды
largest nation that is divided
самый большой народ который разделен
between different states, that's
между разными государствами
right, Syria, Iraq and Turkey, yes, Syria,
правильно сырия ​​Ирак и Турция да сырия
Iran, Iraq and Turkey, after the First
Иран Ирак и Турция после Первой
World War, they should have been
мировой войны должны были проект
make a project Well, when
сделать Ну когда начали появляться
independent states began to appear there in these
независимые государства там на этих
territories after the fall of the Ottoman
территориях после падения османской
Empire and others, it
империи и других
should have been Kurdistan.
должен был быть курдистан Но что-то
And now it turns out that this is what happens
1923 да И сейчас получается вот это что
in Syria, events in Iraq, and everywhere the
В Сирии в ираке.
Kurds turn out, if we look at the masul.  he does
курды получаются вот если массул смотрим
n't
как нет страны и о вас почти Никто не
know. Well, that's correct, as well as how
знает Ну это правильно также как
Ukraine used to be the Soviet Union, and everyone
Украина была вот бы Советский Союз
thought that all Russians live there, but
думали что там живут все русские а там
different peoples live there, as well as how people here think
живут разные народы как здесь думает
that there are some Syrians  Turks, Iraqis,
что есть сирийцы какие-то турки иракцы
Iranians, there are many in Iran, there are a lot of
иранцы Все в иране много есть
Azerbaijanis, there are Persians, there are Kurds,
азербайджанцы есть персы есть курды
yes, that's right. And what kind of Kurdistan are you from,
также Да это правильно А ты из какого
from Turkey? Yes, you get along with
курдистана из Турецкого да получается с
Turkish.
турецкой
ты русский изужал или ты
язык а ты ты русский изучал или ты
уполский или украинский украинский I'm in,
польский или украинский на украинском Я в
come on. It's interesting, and I'm also learning Ukrainian. Can we
давай Интересно а я тоже учу украинский
talk in Ukrainian? Can I?
можно по-украински поговорим могу могу
Well  I understand Russian, too,
Ну я Я понимаю русский тоже меня
Ukrainian is more suitable for Roma.
украинский больше подходит ромов А
Where are you from? Where did you study Ukrainian in
откуда ты где Ты учил украинский в
Ukraine?
Украине я еще в Украине был А где где в
and
я там учил и
worked and studied for whom To the
работал а учился на кого
polytechnic university of applied
политехнический университет прикладная
mathematics Wow programming Well yes, in
математика Вау программирование Ну да в
principle it is interesting interesting And why do
принципе интересно интересно А на чем
you program python python quite
программируешь python python достаточно
unexpectedly Yes and why did you come to
неожиданно Да а почему приехал именно в
Ukraine to teach well
Украину учить
this is the question when  many people
ну это вопрос когда много людей меня
ask me this, it's a little difficult to answer
спрашивают это немного сложно отвечать
because at the moment when I wanted to
потому что на этот момент когда я хотел
teach there were many different
учить было много разных
options, I decided in Ukraine because it
вариантов я в Украине решал потому что там
didn't cost much there, well, it was just
не было много стоил Ну просто было
cheaper than mine.
дешевле
And how long did you live in Ukraine, I'm
ножгу А сколько ты жил в Украине я мейже
about 3 years there  you are three years old and you
т 3 по лет тамму ты три года и ты
speak Ukrainian normally,
нормально говоришь на украинском языке
well, not really very normally, but I
прям не очень очень нормально но я все
still understand and speak a little something No,
одно понимаю и говорю немного что-то Нет
you speak normally, you just
ты нормально говоришь прямо у тебя
have a little accent, well, it is obvious that you are not a native
немного есть акцент ну видно что ты не носитель
speaker, but somewhere  I arrived, I'm not a native speaker, you
языки а где-то приехал я тоже не носитель видишь
see, but I'm already
чуть-чуть если бы но я уже
18, because it's not a native language, you know, well,
18 потому что это не меридный язык знаешь ну я
I learned it,
я выучил
it's interesting, it's interesting.
это интересно интересно Да То ты получается
Yes, you're good.  in
Ну да Есть я знаю Некоторые А как ты видел что в
Kyiv, some people speak Russian, how do
Киеве некоторые говорят на русском языке как
you
ты до этого
feel about it? Well, I don't know, it happens to
относился Ну я я не знаю так бывают
people when they didn't learn the
человек когда они раньше не были
Ukrainian language at school before or what they
украинский язык в школе или что они
studied and now they Well, they don't know
учились и сейчас они Ну они не знают
this this this  It's not their problem. They just didn't
это это не их проблем Они просто не
study. I think so because it's a new,
обучались я так думаю как новый
new generation. I don't know anyone. 15, 20,
новый ну генерация кто-то не знаю 15 20
25 years old, they all know Ukrainian
25 лет они всех знают на украинском
when they taught Ukrainian literature in school.
когда они учили в шкуле ну литературу
Yes, but different. Well, there's still no
Да но другое Ну но все равно нет
difference.  you don't
разницы кто-то каком размо все равно вы не
understand each other, it just turns out that
понимаете друг друга просто получается
I spoke with Ukrainians, they
я общался с украинцами они
told me that when the Soviet Union was in
рассказывали что когда был Советский Союз
Moscow, the Ukrainian language was banned. Just
Москва украинский язык запрещали
like, for example, here in Turkey, where are
как например вот у вас там в Турции
the Kurds  they oppress the Ukrainians here as well, and
курдов притесняют так же и притесняли
Russia oppressed the Ukrainians here, they could not
Россия здесь украинцев они не могли ее
have their own schools because they believed that they
иметь свои школы потому что считали что они
would then be able to secede. Yes, that they
смогут тогда отделиться Да что они
would be able to gain independence.
смогут независимость получить Да и в
Ukrainians were in several states,
украинцы находились в нескольких государствах
Ukrainians were divided in the
украинцы были разделены в
Austro-Hungarian Empire, in the Russian
австровенгерской Империи в Российской
Empire, and when they collapsed, Ukrainians
империи да И когда они рухнули украинцы
had the opportunity to unite into one
получили возможность объединиться в одну
state, the Ukrainian People's
государство было Украинская Народная
Republic  Western Ukrainian, but then
Республика западноукраинская но потом
they were captured again. Yes, you see, what about the Kurds? Well, it
их захватили снова Да Вот видишь а курдам Ну
didn’t work out then, but the Kurds, if I’m not
не получилось тогда но курды если я не
mistaken, there are about 20 or 30 million Kurds, yes,
ошибаюсь курдов где-то 20 млн или 30 да
the population is more, up to 60 million.
население больше до до 60 млн 60ну жди
how many Kurds
хотят показать сколько курдов там
live there, because they get
живеть ну потому что они потом получают
problems later if half Kurds and half well, in
проблем если половин курд и половин ну в
Wikipedia it is written that 30-40 million are in Turkey
Википедия пишет 30-40 млн что в Турции
somewhere  14-20 million in Iran 812 in Iraq 58
где-то 14-20 млйни в Иране 812 в Ираке 58
in Syria 23
в Сирии 23
Yes Well yes but what year is this I don't
Да Ну да но каком каком году этот я не
know it is written in Wikipedia yes oh yes And
знаю это в Википедии написано да о да А
what
какой
data is difficult to
данные тяжело
say well in principle yes well many
сказать ну в принципе да ну много
many I can tell you yes 50 to 60
много могу тебе сказать да 50 до 60
there are millions of Kurds now, well, just in
миллионов курдов есть сейчас ну просто в
Germany, now there are a million and a
Германии сейчас есть миллион из
half Kurds here in Germany living
половины курдов здесь в Германии живет
just in Germany, and there are even more other
просто Германии а есть еще больше другое
European countries, such as the Balkans, I don't know
европесские страны такие Балканы не знаю
Norway, Sweden  there are also there, I now live in the
норве швиден там тоже есть я сейчас живу в
city of Khmelnytskyi in Ukraine,
городе Хмельницкой в ​​Украине
Khmelnytskyi, and there is also a bazaar, a
Хмельницкой да и здесь тоже здесь есть базар
large market there, and there were Turks and Kurds there before the war, and there
большой рынок и там до войны тоже были
were some, and even once there was
Турки и курты были некоторые и даже было
some kind of misunderstanding between the Kurds and the
какие-то как это недоразумения между курдами и
Turks here in the diaspora, there was something there and  it's
турками здесь диаспорой что-то там было и
so interesting what we thought about the echoes
так интересно что мы думали о отголосках
reached here in Ukraine, it's interesting Well, I don't
дошли сюда в Украину интересно Ну я не
know, of course there are good and bad people in all people,
знаю конечно у всех народ есть добро и
that's normal, but what do I
плохие люди это это нормально но что я
know about Turks  Turk, they don't
о турцах знаю турк они о не
accept the
акцептуют
other, it's a bit problematic, you know.
другому это проблематично немного знаешь
For example, we're talking now, if you're
К примеру мы разговариваем сейчас если ты
Kurt. And I'm a Turk, I don't accept you,
Курт А я турк я тебя не акцептирую
nothing, but it doesn't work like that, we're
просто ничего но так не получается мы
two people sitting here. Well, let's
два человека здесь сидим Ну давай будем
accept each other and let's
друг друга акцептовать и будем разум
live without problems, we'll just  in peace,
жить без проблем мы будем просто в мире
you know, they never work out, they
знаешь а они так и не получаются они
just look here, I understand why, because it
просто здесь смотри я понимаю почему как
seems to me that the Turks perceive the Kurds as the
мне кажется турки воспринимают курдов как
Russians perceive the Ukrainians, but the Russians
россияне воспринимают украинцев от россияне
once captured us that way and they perceived
когда-то нас захватили так и они воспринимали
that  we are part of their state and that's all,
что вот мы часть их государства и все
and we are not a people, we are not this one, and in
и мы не народ мы не этот так же в
principle, I don't know how the Turks communicate with you there.
принципе я не знаю как турки с вами там
Yes, but
общаются Да но
eh, Turkey is also the Turks, they came
ее Турция она ведь тоже турки пришли
from those lands where Turkmenistan is, that's it, yes,
ее из тех краев где Туркменистан вот это да
they came to  the Anatolian peninsula was
они пришли на анатолийский полуостров
captured, and there was Byzantium,
и захватили там же было Византия была
and Byzantium was, yes, they captured Armenia, and they used to
Византия была да захватили и ну Армения а
live there, but after the Turks
там там жили раньше но после турцев
came there, you know, you know, there
приехали там они просто знаешь
will be genocide when they just happen
гносай геносайд когда просто будут
Dying everywhere, yes, they are a very big
Умирать всё да они очень велик
genocide during the Ottoman Empire. There are so
геносид на время Османской импе
many Armenian Kurds, there is even a city
много это даже есть такие города когда
called Ders. I don’t know if you know there are
называется дерс Не знаю если знаешь там
thousands and thousands of people in Armenia. The
просто в тысячи в тысячи людей Армении
Kurds are just what genocidal people are. Well, that’s how it
курдов они просто какие гносаюд и Ну да
was. In short, they are just  they don't
и было Короче они они просто не
accept the other if they just
акцептуют другому если просто они
say Let's
будут сказать Давай будем какие брать
live together, I think there wo
вместе жить я думаю никакого проблематично
n't be any problems, but you know it's unpleasant, for example,
не будет но это знаешь неприятно например
you live in Ukraine now, and the Russians say we  we
Ты сейчас в Украине жи а россияне скажи мы
don't want you, even you, we don't
тебя не хотим даже ты мы тебя не
want you, you live in your own house, well, I
хотим ты жишь на свой дом Хорошо я тебя
don't bother you, I'm not in your house, I just live
не беспокою я не в твой дом Я просто живу
in a quiet place, in my house, without problems, I
в спокойный на мой дом без проблем Я
don't bother you, please get away from
тебя не беспокою пожалуйста встани от
me, but they will still say no, you  you
меня но все равно они скажут нет ты
can't live, for example, you're not, you're not
не можешь жить например ты не ты не
a person, so it doesn't work, well, people. You
человек то это не получается ну людей Ты
have a word, and I'll say fine, if I'm not
же есть сл и буду сказать хорошо если я не
a person, then let's go, let's go.
человек тогда Давай пойдем
unfortunately, there are many good
пока еще есть в Турции на жал много хороших
people, I won’t say all of them, but you can remove
людей я не скажу всех но можешь снять
one. Well, look, Turkey
такись Ну потому что смотрите Турция
has the Phantom of the Empire, because there was an
Она имеет Фантом империи потому что была
Ottoman Empire, they controlled
Османская империя они контролировали
huge
огромные
territories of modern Israel, Palestine,
территории современной там Израиля палестина
Egypt, Iraq, and so on, just like the
Египта Ирака и так далее да так же как
Russian Empire, it controlled and  the
Российская империя она контролировала и в
Russians have this Phantom of the loss of
россиян вот этот Фантом потери там
some kind of greatness there. And I understand that
величия какой-то И я так понимаю что в
Turkey also has a little bit, yes,
Турции тоже немного есть да
they are still on this on this opinion what on
они пока еще на это на это мнение что на
this  dreams You could say that they will once
этот снов Можно бы сказать что они будут
again return to such moments
еще раз вернуться к таким моментам
when they were in the Ottoman Empire, but
когда были Османской империи но ну
today it is not so,
сегодняшний день это не так
life has already changed, so
получается жизнь уже поменял
technology has changed them all, but if
тактехнология поменял всех они вот если
we look at Europe, Austria was the
мы посмотрим Европу Австрия была
Austro-Hungarian Empire, Austria has no
австро-венгерская империя в Австрии нет
claims to  neighboring countries she lives for herself
претензий на соседние государства она себе
she lives a lot she is developing
живет она много жива она развивается
everyone on the contrary wants to go to Austria but
все наоборот хотят в Австрию вот
Britain yes Once upon a time there was also an empire of half the
Британия да Когда-то тоже была империя
world Yes now whatever she says I will
полмира Да сейчас что она же не говорит я
take it  yes, sorry, Britain, I, I know,
захватю да Извини Британия я я знаю
when were you in Iraq, well, Britain, where are
когда были в Ираке Британия откуда
you from, Iraq, you were so big there, you don't
Ирак ты там такая большая была такой не
know, you were so strong, she was in Iraq, she was in
знаешь такая сила была в ираке она была в
Africa, I don't know, well, what am I going to say, because
Африке не знаю Ну что я то Скажу потому что
today, Look, they, they have,
а сегодня Смотрите Ну они у них есть
they can  if they want, I don't know
они можно если они хотят не знаю
how many countries they can take, but
сколько страна они можно забрать
there are no such thoughts to
такой такие мнения нет на сегодняшний
date, because why do I need to
день потому что за что за что мне нужно
do this,
так делать
what's the point?
россияпась в Украине ни каком смысле почему я
so do it so that they do bad things.
надо так делать, чтобы они плохо делали
Well, if for example they do something bad in
Ну хорошо если например они пдеть в
Russia, what kind of terrorists are they doing? I
России они делаете какие
don't know, partisans or what's
террористки не знаю партизанцы или что
good. I protest or respond to them,
хорошо я их которые протесту или отвечаю
but they're just people. They're calm.  there's
но ну просто человек они спокойны питает
just nothing, there's
они тебя не мешают они просто ничего
no reason why you're doing this. And for the
нет причины почему ты так поступаешь А для
Kurds in Turkey, they're just the same. Well,
курди в Турции так же они просто Ну
I'll say it. You just don't
буду сказать Ты просто будет меня тобе и не
like me, and I want you not to be here.
понравится и я хочу, чтобы ты здесь не был
And no one will sext  do you know? Do you
все А никто не будет секситировать знаешь Ты
know such a
знаешь такого
Ukrainian poet as Vasyl
украинского поэта как Василий
Symonenko? Well, I've heard that name. He has a
Симоненко Ну я слышал это имя у него есть
poem for a Kurdish brother. Do you know this poem?
стихотворение куртскому брату Знаешь это стихотворение
No, but if you want, I'll read it
нет а хочет я прочту
to you. The stoop is called to fight to fight,
тебе ступ называется бороться побороть
as Shevchenko used to say. Yes, and he wrote it for a Kurd. He
как Шевченко говорил Да и ну это для курда
had a
он написал У него был
yes.  the mountains are crying out with blood, the broken
да взывают горы кровью политые подбитые
stars are falling down into the smelly valleys, wounded
звезды падают вниз в пахнущие долины изранены
and torn, hungry chauvinism is
и срытые вторгается голодный швинизм о
attacking the Kurds, live their bullets, but the lives of murderers  don't
курде жи свои патроны но жизнь убийц не
spare the tyrants arbitrariness and robbery, a
щади на байстрюков произвола и разбоя
bloody tornado, fall, have
кровавым смерчим бурию упади веди из
a conversation with them with bullets, they came not
ими пулями разговор они пришли не
only for kindness, they came to take
только за добром пришли забрать имя
your name, your language, let your son be a tyrant
твое язык пустить твоего сына байстрюком
with the oppressor, you will not live in harmony with him;  the
с угнетателем не будешь жить в согласии ему
enemy is the fiercest
измученных народов наш враг злейший
chauvinism, he has engaged villainy with shame with
шовинизм он ломство обручил позором из
shame. He will do anything  so that
позором Он сделает все чтоб
you surrender, O Kurd. Take care of your bullets,
покорился ты о курде Береги свои патроны
without them, you will not save your family, do not
без них тебе свой род не уберечь не
lull the power of hatred, then you will
укачивай ненависти силу тогда
take kindness as a motto, how will you fall
приветливость вы возьмешь за девиз как упадет
into an open grave, the last chauvinist on the planet,
в развязанную могилу последний на планете
you can tell me coolly,
шовинист Классно ты можешь мне сказать
be kind, Vasyl Symonenko, and I will
Пожалуйста Василий Симоненко А я
write to you right now, you can  write me I
тебе сейчас напишу можешь меня писать Я
want
хочу
it Vasyl Symonenko to the Kurdish
это Василий Симоненко курдскому
brother so
брату да
thank you Well you see Taras on from Taras
спасибо Ну видишь это Тараса на от Тарас
Shevchenko wrote something about the Kurds No no  it's
Шевченко о курдах что-то написал Нет ни это
not Taras Shevchenko, it's Vasyl Semenenko,
не Тарас Шевченко это Василий Семененко
he just started with the first line, he
просто он начал первой строчкой
signed it like Taras Shevchenko's motto was to
подписал как у Тараса Шевченко девиз был
fight, he won't, he didn't use it I
бороться поборе не он использовал Я
thought it was written by Will No, it's not Tara, it's
думал это Виль написал Нет нет не тара это
Vasyl Symonenko Vasyl Symonenko, the author of
Василий Симоненко Василий Симоненко автор
Kurtsky bratov yes to Kurtsky brother yes
куртских братьев да куртских братьев да
This is you to whom Kurtsky brother  Yes Well, it is
Это тебе кому куртскому брату Да Ну
interesting Yes, that is,
интересно Да то есть
you see our poets when they were oppressed by
видишь наши поэты когда подавлялись
Russia, yes, they also understood that the
Россию да они также понимали что в
Kurts had a similar problem to us Yes, but
куртов довольно схожая с нами беда Да но
you see, Ukraine succeeded in Ukraine  it did
видишь Украине удалось Украине удалось
n't work right away either, because at the beginning of the 10th
е тоже не сразу потому что в начале X
century we gained a state, but then
век мы получили государство но потом
lost it, and the Soviet Union attacked
потеряли ее да Советский Союз напал
Poland in 1991, we still made
Польше в 91 году мы все же сделали
a state, and now you see, Russia wants to
государство и сейчас видишь Россия хочет снова
attack us again, so I don't know how you feel,
нас погубить поэтому я не знаю как у вас
how is it  It will be Years ago that you have a
да как оно будет Через годы потому что у вас
very difficult region, yes. Yes,
очень сложный регион да Да
many people do not want to.
много людей когда не хотят
There is the Far East. Oh, no, the Far East. And
Е Там Дальний Восток Ой не Дальний Восток А
this is exactly the Meridian of the Euphrates Tiger. All of them are
как раз Междуречие тигра ефрата эти все
there.  from time immemorial it was a fertile land, it is
Да там изначально была плодородная земля это
still Babylon and so on, and
еще же там Вавилон и так далее да и еще
Alexander the Great came there,
Александр Македонский туда приходил
the Persians came there, what nations did not
Персы приходили какие народы только не
come, because it was once a
приходили так как это было когда-то
very, very rich region with a very ancient
очень-очень богатый регион с очень древней
history, and now, too,
историей ну сейчас сейчас тоже очень очень
they have very, very much, you know  oil and
знаешь такой нефт
gas, but now you don’t want it for anyone, for example, you
газ а сейчас никому не хочешь например
don’t want to give it to Iraq, well, Kurstan
не хочет дать в иракене курстанский
Iraq has a lot of oil, a lot of
Ирак там очень много нефт очень много
gas, and I read what they said, it can take
газ а я читал что они сказал может дать
10 years to give gas in Europe simply
10 лет дать газ в Европе просто
I understand Kurdish gas in Iraq, I
курдский газ в ираке понял я
understand that Masul is exactly in
пойму что масул это же как раз в
Iraqi Kurdistan, and for just 10 more
иракскому курдистану да еще на просто 10
years, it can give gas to all of Europe without any
лет может дать всех европ газ без без
problems, and
без проблем, а как тебя зовут Меня
what is your name?  surname Nasirov
насыр это же имя от фамилия Насыров
nasir what what does the name nasir nasir mean
насыр что это означает имя насырь насырь
this is an Arabic name Arabic Arabic
это это арабское имя арабское арабское
Ugu name
Угу имя
[music]
[музыка]
this is well in English I  yes vktoory who is
это ну поанглийски я таки вктоory кто
victory victory yes winner yes o And
победа победа да победитель да о А у
you have exactly Kurdish names Well, of course And
вас есть именно курдские имена Ну да конечно
what are Kurdish names so that they are not Arabic and for
какие курдские такие чтобы не арабски а
example I have brothers I have three
например у меня братьев У меня есть три
brothers they are
брать они
Hemen
гемен
Razzgar Bajdar they are Kurdish they are not
разгар баждар они курдские они не
Arabic
арабский Угу
Ugushsky in direct Kur  another question: the Kurds
ски прям кур еще такой вопрос курды
celebrate Navruz. Well, Navruz, yes.
празднуют праздник навруз Ну да навруз да
In other words, you still
То есть вы получаете еще
treat the Tajiks the same way, but
относиться так же как и таджики да вот
they  Arabs There is no Navruz
они до у арабов Нет наруха
no in Arabic there is no Navruz this is exactly it
нет у арабий нет это наврус это как раз это
if the spring equinox yes When the Sun
если весеннее равноденствие да Когда Солнце
Yes this is Navru our new year
Так это навру наш новый год
we will say when will be the first day
мы скажем когда будет первый день
of I 21 in March it will be Yes That is the
у я 21 в март это будет Да То есть
spring equinox yes zama ends
весеннее равноденствие да заканчивается
some new life begins we  there will
начинается какая-то новая жизнь
be such a feast, they will be affectionate. Well, this
зава будет таки часты они будут Ну
is called Navruz, yes, I know, it is
да и это навруз называется да знаю
interesting.
интересно Да и интересно что много вот этих
Navrus because with the
дальше сохранили наврус потому что из
arrival of Islam in this territory,
приходом е Ислама на этой территории Да
just as with the arrival of Christianity in Europe,
же как с приходом христианства в Европу
many
очень много
traditional holidays disappeared or were
традиционных праздников исчезли или
transformed in European countries, they
трансформировались в европейских странах
also celebrated Navrus, but it
тоже праздновали вот Как у вас наврус только
was called in a different way, it was the spring
по-другому называлось это было весеннее
equinox, a solar holiday, yes, interesting.
равноденствие солнечный праздник да интересно
Us, for example, Navrus is not religious at all.
Да у нас например наврус это вообще не
It's just national, you can
религиозные Это просто национальные
say. Not religious. Well, because there is
сказать Не религий Ну потому что потому
no religious Navrus in Islam, that's why you
религиозный в исламе нет навруза поэтому вы
Kurds are now Muslims, so in principle
курды сейчас мусульмане да в принцип
Jews, Muslims, Christians, all
евреи мусульмане христиане всх разное
different, different Yes,
разное Да курдие
Kurds, and the Izidis are Kurds, there are Yazidis, too, Kurt
а изид это курдов есть дазиды во тоже Курт
They, too, Kurt, it’s just a religion, it’s
Они тоже Курт просто религия это езиды
called Yazidis, I know a few of them, but
называется вот я я знаю их немного но
they are a very closed group, yes, the Izidis, well, their
они очень замкнута Группа да изид ну их
religion is so great that no one can
религия так очень никто не может ну на
accept their religion  in Yezidi to another to another
принять лигии на езиде к другому другому
to Yezidi they are just I'm a Yezidi my wife
к езиде они просто я еезид моя жена
here we have children wake up And no one can
сди у нас детей буди А никто не может на
change to another religion  to us a little Well,
другому религии поменять в наше немного
such a law is closed closed yes
Ну такой закон замкнут замкнут да
such a group yes and what is the name of
такая группа да а как у изидов называется
this very main holy city among the Izidis
это самый главный город
as in Iraq Iraq Well how does the sound disappear I
как в ираке ираке Ну как пропадает звук Я
think
думаю
now now
сейчас сейчас
now because I once read yes I am curious about them
сейчас я когда-то читал да о них мне
lalish yes lalish yes main  the shrine of Isis
лалиш да лалиш да главная святыня Изида
Yes, it
Да
goes like this vkurstan Dohva district Dohva
ходится так вкурстан дохва район дохва
Yes in Iraq in Ira in Iraqi Kurdistan
Да в Ираке у Ира в иракском курдистане
ugh and you have Assyrians
угу а ассирийцы есть у
in us
вас у нас
in  There is no Uvaza in Turkey, or not, Syrians,
в Турции нет внимания или не сирийцы
Assyrians,
ассирийцы
Assyrians, I thought so, say, there are
ассирий я думал это скажет ассирийцы очень
many Assyrians, there are many, yes, they are Christians, they are
много есть много да они христиане они
Christians. Yes, but they are different, for example,
христиане Да но разные никакие например
Ukrainian Christians.
украинские христиане они вижу когда у
And
что они тоже живут ну на одном городе А
we do have a michit and a church, I see it
у нас таки мечет и церковь я там вижу и
there too. Well, I know how they do what they do
там Ну я знаю как они как занимаются
there, it’s like the Ukrainians, yes, and the Assyrians, who are
там это как и украинцы угу а ассирийцы которые
not Christians, what else  avest, are there avestians
не христиане какие еще авесту авестийцы есть
or not,
чуть ли не христиане
are there christians, is there a religion, it is still called zrdeshi,
есть религия это еще называется зрдеши
when they believe in
когда они верят в
the sun, well, there is avestia, there are assyrians. Well, there are
солнце ну там есть авестиция там есть ассир Ну
many more Armenians, when they used
много еще армень когда раньше очень раньше
to live there.  the
там жили все равно здесь там живет Ну да
European territories of Christianity and Islam,
европейские территории христианства Ислама
all believed in solar religions, all in
все верили в солнечные какие-то религии все в
different variations. And look at the Kurds, which
разные вариации А смотри к курдам какой
people are closer to each other?
народ более близкий
Well, close, I don’t know.  but
по больше Ну близкий не знаю такие но
with us, for example, the Kurds have very, very good
у нас например курдов очень-очень хорошо
contact
имеют контакт
with, I heard that with
с я такой слышал из
the Jew and from Armenia, well, the Armenians are still Armenia,
евреим и из армены ну армены таки Армения
what a good Jew, because before, when I
какой хорошо еврей потому что раньше когда пока
had not yet been to Israel, there were a lot of Jews
еще не был в Израиль очень много евреев
living there, well, with the Kurds, they were simply
там жил ну с курдым они просто были
together Ugh  Of course, I didn't see it, but my
заодного Угу Я конечно не видел таки
dad and my uncle, for example,
папа и мой Ну например дядя такки
they told me that they
они рассказывали что
were there, for example, now there is a street with no
там имелись к примеру сейчас улица не
name, such a Jewish name, but after when
имя такие еврейское имя Но после когда
Israeli,
израильский
well, the country is called, they all
ну называется страна они такие всех
came there, they didn’t come from where they were from. Well,
пришли к там они не откуда были Ну
they spoke Kurdish without such, but they
разговаривали куртский без такой но
were simply Jews, they were not
просто религии были евреи они не были
Muslim, but look, no, I meant
мусманы а вот смотри ну нет я имел в виду
no. How normal or not I am on the ultrasound, but
не Как нормально или не я на УЗИ вот
relatives Yes, for example  if we
родственные Да Вот например если мы
take the Turks and Azerbaijanis there, they are
возьмем там Турки и азербайджанцы они
almost similar. But what kind of peoples are similar to the
почти ну похожие А вот какие похожи на
Kurds, do you know about the history of my
курдов народы ты знаешь об истории моей
Indo-European people, yes, yes, here I am  Well,
индоеропский народ да да Да вот я же
that is, you are with the Persians, with others,
то есть получается вы с персами с другими
who is the most similar to
кто Кто ближе похож на
you? Well, the Persians are the Persians, they are. I think they are not
вас Ну перса перс это они Я думаю не
Indo-European, they are Indo-European, yes, the
индоевропейские они индоевропейски да
Indo-European people are
индоевропейский народ
Per, to be honest, I do not know for sure,
пер я если честно я не точно точно знаю
but I know for sure, yes, for sure, we are Turks, for example,
но я точно знаю да точно мы например
they are a little  they are different, I
на туркам турк они немного поразятся
can tell you a lot. Well, Turks,
они могу тебе сказать Много Ну турки
they are Turks, they are Turks, Plana Turks, Oghuzs,
они тюрки они тюрки плана тюрки огузы
they are like Azerbaijanis, like Turkmen,
они как азербайджанцы как туркмены
for example, Indo-European, we can say  I do
например индоевропейски может сказать ее я
n't know exactly in history, but what kind of Turks do
не знаю точно в истории но Турки
we teach, what
Мы учим они
Tatars are they?
татар какие татарстаны в которые Китай на
lives and the
с другим кто там на этот регион живет и
people have changed because if you
народ поменял потому что если будешь
look at the pure Turks, they look a little like
смотреть чистые Турцы они похожи немного
them, you can tell China what
на такие можно тебе сказать Китае какие ну
I am, yes, I looked. About the Kurds, yes, the
я вот я да я посмотрел Про курдов да
Kurds belong to the Iranian peoples,
курды относятся к иранским народам
yes, yes  Ira yes, that is, it turns out that they are close to you,
да Да Ира да то есть получается к вам
this is what comes out. There are Persians. Yes, and so
близкие это выходит Там Перси Да и так
on. And Ani, here they write
далее от Ани вот пишут близкие к
the Ristanci, who are close to Darden. And so on, other
дарденные рстанцы Ну и так далее другие
Indo-Aryans.
индоарийцы
Yes, in principle, this is what we
да Ну в принципе да мы
look like.
смотримся да ну и к вам близки эти
they live in India, yes, in the north of
живут Индия да на севере
India, I don’t know. I just know it.
Индии я Ну не знаю Просто я это знаю
For example, they are Arabs. No, they are Arabs. They are
Например арабы они сами Нет арабы они
Semites. Yes, Semites, they are not
семиты и семиты что они не разно ну
different. Well, we are different.
вообще мы разно смотримся на вид
we look a little different. And we are so ethnic, but
немножко по-разно А мы так спермато но
Indorpian, but all the same now because there are
индорпски но все равно сейчас потому что есть
people who live in Iraq or in Syria, they
люди когда в Ирак живут или в Сирии они
just mix, yes, mix. Ugh, we
просто ну смешивается да смешивается Угу
changed,
менялись
but anyway, well, not all 100%, what
е но все равно Ну не всех 100% что
changed?  let's say the same
поменял еще поражение Да так же скажем
if people live in Ukraine,
если люди жи вот те что в Украине жилит
yes, the Scythians, Sarmatians, Goths took part in the development of this people,
Да в развитии этого народа приняли участие
yes, that is,
там Скифы сарматы готы да то есть оно же
they brought different waves  a little bit of their
разные волны они привносили немножко своего
genetic material and therefore if we take,
генетического материала и потому если брать
say, Ukrainians and Kurds - they are
скажем и украинцы да И курды – это
Indo-European peoples and Germans,
индоевропейские народы и немцы да
but interacting with various other
но взаимодействуя с разными другими
cultures, peoples and so on, yes, they have changed
культурами народами и так далее
over thousands of years, in 3-4 5 years
за тысячи лет там за 3-4 5 ся лет
they have changed and, for example, are not similar
они поменялись и например не похожи
each other Well, yes, that's right.
друг на друга Ну да да и правильно
Well, for example, we are abroad in an
Ну например мы за до границы в
Arab country, well, that's it, and of course we
арабской стране ну это это а конечно мы
have more contact than
имеем больше контакт чем
a little can say in Turkish. And at the
немцело можно сказать в Турке А на этот
moment  we have more contact with a Turk,
момент мы имеем больше контакт с турцем
for example, Kurt, maybe a Turkish girl
например Курт может турецкий девушка
or a Turkish girl, in short, you live in the same
или турецкая девушка с короче вы в одной
country, yes, it changes if,
государству да живете поменяется если
for example, Kurds and Poles or
например курдов и поляков или курдов
Ukrainian Kurds or Kurds and Germans, they were
украинцев или курдов и немцев они были
Susi Oh, listen, this is an interesting question, yes, the
суси О слушай вот интересный вопрос да
Kurdish language is also
получается курдский язык она тоже
Indo-European  language Anu, count in
индоевропейский язык Ану посчитай на
Kurdish to 10. I'm interested. How will it be?
куртские до 10ти Мне интересно од Как будет
pench shashtse shst
пенч шоссе шст
fce cm
фото см
VM but where is
ВМ но где
it yes it is 10 i.e. it is quite similar yes to
е да это 10 то есть достаточно похоже на
Ukrainian some counterparts a little
украинские какие-то ответчики немного на
yes because and here four will repeat
да потому что и а вот четыре еще раз повторить
four charms yes it is like in many
четыре чар да оно начи у очень многих
Indo-European languages ​​na na on this as
индоевропейских языках на этом как
it is in Sanskrit также  there chatur or is
оно на санскрите также там чатур или
it called something interesting Yes
как-то оно называется интересно Да
anu anu say Here are such words as dad mom
ану ану скажи Вот такие слова как папа мама
in Kurdish e baba baba is dad
на куртском е баба баба - это папа
fazae Yes yes dad and mom are ee  dyke
фазае Да да папа и мама - это ее дайк
dak well and son daughter
да ну а сын дочь
e Kits This is daughter
е Kits Это дочь
kor And like milk
кор А как молоко
p in a different way
г по-другому
you give milk
давите моло
i.e. the numbers are very similar numbers are very similar
то есть числа очень похожие числа очень похожие
yes in general when will there be for example 100 200
да вообще когда быть например 100 200
300 This is Ukrainian We will also say for
300 Это украинский Мы тоже скажет
example 100 we will say garden garden yes And
например 100 мы скажем сад сад да А
look at  there is such a thing as a garden in linguistics,
смотри на счет сад в лингвистике есть
there is a whole group of peoples who have ee cent
такое есть целая группа народов у которых ее цент
and garden, yes, in Latin, cent ee, we have 100,
и сад да вот в латыни цент ее у нас 100 у
you have a garden on this side  it's
вас сад по эту сторону оно да Сотка
called Sotka, it's somehow interesting. Well, it's
называется так как-то интересно Ну это это
similar in general, for example
вообще похоже например
100 garden 200 dusad 300 garden 400 charsad
100 сад 200 дусад 300 сад 400 черсад
charsa And how will the sun
чарса А как будет солнце
Rozh
Рож
No there is nothing similar And what Kurdish words do you know that are
Нет нет похожего А какие ты знаешь от слова
similar to Ukrainian because you
курдские которые похожи на украинский потому что ты
know both Kursk and Ukrainian  well, it is similar to
знаешь и курскую и украинскую ну похоже на
Ukrainian, for example,
украинский Например
we are
мы
Samovar. We also say Samovar kazan is a
Самовар Мы тоже говорим Самовар казан это
cauldron, well kazan is Turkic, yes kazan in our
котел ну котел это тюркка да котел в нашу
language  Ukrainian, yes, it
язык в украинском да и
came to yours from the Turkic peoples,
в ваше пришло из тюркских народов
that is, the Turks, yes, in fact, we had contacts
то есть турки да по существу мы имели контакты
with the Turks, and you had contacts with the Turks,
с турками и вы имели контакты с турками
and that's why kazan got into our languages ​​from
да поэтому казан это в наши языки попало из
Turkish. We have it.
турского У нас есть Ну как ты сказал
also from Turkic it was possible no yes in
тоже из тюрских можно было не так
Ukrainian there is no Pokurska there is also no
по-украински нет покурски тоже нет
when something is not there for example no yes And there
когда что-то нет например нетда А
is no
нет да
yes there is no Pokurska itself There is no but how is there is there is
же покурски сам нет Нет а как
g
есть есть г
Yes a little sho And there is no yes
Ага немножко схо А нет да
it is  There will be. And it’s not at all interesting.
это будет А это до вообще са интересно и е
What’s
что
this? What’s in Kursk, what’s Ukrainian? Well,
это Что по-курски что по-украински Ну
in Russian, yes, in Ukrainian, what’s
по-русски да с по-украински что да по
in Kurdish, how is it going to happen? It’s cool. Well, tell me, tell me, tell me in
Прикольно А ну скажи скажи по курам скажи
Kurdish, what kind of ram is this?  eh ava
на курдском языке что это за баран е ава
baran avatse Yes And if Well yes damn what
баран авате Да А если Ну да да блин какой
other words can you say Yes to be similar it's
еще слова можешь такие Да чтобы похожи аж
interesting
интересно
Uhu well brother it's bra bra o bra brother it's bra
Угу ну брат это бра бра о бра брат это бра
ee
ее
[music]
[музыка]
Well I  I don't know, there are a lot of them, but
Ну я не знаю очень многое но на этом А
there is a
как будет там камень гора
stone, a mountain, a
камень это Берт Бер или а гора
stone.
чя чя а дерево дар
for example, a horse can be
знали дерево Да например конь может
different from a horse. How will you have a horse?
отличаться конь Как у вас будет Лошадь -
This is an ASP about the fact that when we say
это АСП о том что когда е скажем
Ukrainian, German, there is
украинский немецкий там
also a Kurdish people, their ancestors have already
и курдский народ их предки еще уже
split up, so and so had a tree and a
разошлись дерево было и у тех и тех а
horse  appeared, for example, later about that
лошадь появилась например позже о том
see a tree der Anu say four
види а дерево дер Ану скажи четыре
trees
деревья
char dar And say a ram stands near
чар дар А скажи баран стоит возле
four trees a ram in
четырех деревьев баран в
vastava ay-yay wait wait somewhere nok
васставы ай-яй жди жди десенок
sign say a ram stands near four
знок скажи баран стоит около четырех
trees ram vastava barambar char dar a
древ баран вастава барамбар чар дар а
stands vastala how  vasta vastav became became
стоит вастала как васта вастал стал стал
standing
стоит
cool interesting quite interesting conversation
прикольно интересно довольно интересный разговор
Yes yes yes a lot a lot a lot a lot a
Да да да очень много очень много очень
lot female now I don't remember
много саммите сейчас я не помню назад
because I don't know how you like but a lot That's
что я не знаю как тебе но очень много Да
right for example
именно например
in general  no, it’s not at all Kurtz, because
вообще нет это вообще куртски назад
it’s very quick to say no, but
что мытиж очень многое сказать А
there’s no, there’s
гя нет такки
no, there’s no, what’s up, what’s
есть нет Нет а что Что хочет Ну чай это у
up?  the
пришло с востока и уже мы переняли это
word so that for example A cow how
слово так что на например А корова как
will it be manga manga
будет манга манга
manga there are two names manga or
манга там есть два имени манга или
cyr cyr well they are like that cow has two names
цир цир ну такие они корова имеет два имени
and water how
а вода как
will it be
будет
Au like
Ау как
Au av something in Greek like Aqua  Is
Ау ав что-то на греческие как Аква там
it there? It's water. It's interesting.
или Ау Это вода Ау интересно
And we have, for example,
А у нас есть например
piavaz, it's
пиваз это
zwibli
плести
. What can you say like that, and here's
Что можно сказать так а вот
eggplant lazhan - it's
баклажанлажан - это
banyan, apple - it's
банжан яблока – это
sev, you, in Kurdish, you're
сев ты ты по-курдски ты
like that, that, that, that, that, see,
как ту ту да ту то да види
yes,
да
that's interesting.
йте да интересно
the alphabet that the Kurds write,
а алфавит который у курдов пишете
which one do they have two, they have such a Latin one,
каким вот имеют два имеют такой латинский
and that Which is Arabic and Arabic, that is, it
и то Какой арабский и арабский то есть
turns out that there
получается был при е еще Османской
was still a Latin alphabet in the Ottoman Empire. And when
империи был латинским А когда в Турции
Mustafa Kemal was translating the reform in Turkey  You were
Мустафа кемаль переводил реформу то вас
also reformed like this. Well, yes,
тоже реформировали так выходы Ну да Да
for example, Kurds in Turkey, when in Turkish
например Турции курдил когда в турецкие
they now live in the English alphabet. And
сейчас живет они английский алфабет А
someone in Iraq lives in Iraqi, because the
кто-то в ираке живет они по-иракски потому что
state understood it, but in principle,
государство это понял но ну в принципе
it is not very problematic, that is why the language itself is
это не очень проблематично поэтому сама речь
simply in different letters in different, as it
просто на разных буквах на разный как
is called  attribution yes interesting
называется приписание да интересно
And for example
А например
from famous Kurds So who can you
из известных курдов Так кого ты можешь
name So who would we
назвать Вот кого бы мы
know?
знали Ну что Что ты не ну там как-то учёный
people, who is
курдисно я из известных людей кто
Kurt? Well, now I don't know what to tell you.
Курт Ну сейчас я не знаю что тебе сказать
Well, for example, a very, very long time ago, who was
Ну например очень-очень давно кто из были
called Salagadin Ayubi, do you know him?
называется салагадин аюби ты его знаешь
He was, how can you say, the president of
он был как тебе сказать президент до
all Muslims in Sala, so
всех мусульмански во сала и против
he fought against the Christ-bearers, and he was a Kurd.
христоносцев он воевал а он курдом был
I thought he was an Arab.  No, he was a Kurd. I'll
Я думал он араб Нет он курдом был Ану
take a look. I thought he was on slaves. No,
посмотрю Я думал что он на раблах о Нет
he was Naro, but he was born in Tirkit,
он ну он Наро а родился в тирките в
Iraq. It's
Ираке
so cool that you can
да прикольно а просто его то может
watch him. What kind of people is he?  Kurt And
смотреть Какой его народ Ну он Курт А
what
что
else do we have, but at the moment I don't
еще у нас много есть но я на данный момент не
remember a lot of us, a poet as a poet
помню у нас много п поэт как поэт
is called poets, poets Ah Uhu, there
называется поэты поэты Ах Угу много
are many poets,
поэты есть
and on Ahmad Shavky, he is
а на ахмад шавки такой
very, very, how can you tell,
очень-очень как можно тебе сказать
popular in Iraq for this region  they
популярные в Ираке на этот регион они
were this is this old man Once upon a time he was Yes yes
были это это старый Когда-то он был Так да
yes a very, very long time ago they are because our
да очень-очень давно они потому что наша
language is Kursk they
язык по курски язык они
call it Poti language i.e. it is very suitable Well
называют поти язык то есть очень подходит
just
Ну просто
write well Let's say
пиши ну Скажем
so much I don't remember at the moment
так много я на данный момент не помню
So anu  Now I'll see if they write
Да авось сейчас посмотрю так да пишут
about what Salakhodin
о чем салаходин был этот
really was. Well, there's
действительно Ну там есть
Vinkurt for me, it's a surprise, I didn't know,
винкурт для меня это удивление я не знал
no, he's Kurt, but he worked in
нет нет он он Курт но он работал на
Arabic, I can say the people, and
арабский могу сказать народ и
he took a lot of Ukraine, I don't know, went
он много Украины забрал не знаю пошел
to Hungary, I don't know or Spain  In my opinion, he did
в Венгрию Я не знаю или Испании Италии
not leave Italy,
не кнри
he simply fought back from the
он по-моему он просто отбил от
Crusaders of the modern land, where
крестоносцев земли современной там где
there were battles in Jerusalem, in my
Иерусалим там были битвы по-моему Ну да
opinion.
Так он там взял я думал если то честно
I remember
помню
Ugu at such a moment, yes, he is
Угу на такой момент да а он этот
Salahadin, he is Kurt, he is Kurt. Well, because
салахадин Он Курт он Курт Ну потому что
of the history
на истории
that we taught at school, what was he at that
что мы учили в школе что он на этот
moment when he was? Oh, yes, with the president.
момент когда он был.
He was talking to another of his cousins, I don't
Он разговаривал с другом его кузине не
know someone in a second language  mi in
знаю кто-то на втором языке мы на
Arabic
арабский
zero then we will say This now we have a
нули тогда скажем Это сейчас у нас больше
state there and a state language yes and
есть там государство и государственный язык да а
before there was a caliphate there or this and there
раньше был там халифат какой-нибудь или этот а
could be a lot of languages ​​in each
языков могло быть очень много в каждом
region in fact there was simply its own
регионе фактически просто был свой
governor who collected money from  of this
наместник который собирал деньги с этого
region, and people lived there in their own
региона а люди жили себе там своими
languages. Well, it used to be like that before, well,
языках Ну так раньше раньше так и было
we have, for example, in Kurdish, there
раньше ну у нас например на курдском
are many different dialects, but
тоже есть много разных диалектов но все
still people understand each other. Well, you have
одно люди понимают друг друга Ну у вас
many dialects, because
много Да диалектов ибо вы получаете
you are, your ethnic community is scattered throughout  in
вы ваше этническое сообщество разбросано по
different territories, there with the Arabs, there with the
разных территориях там с арабами там с
Turks, there with the Iranians, it’s the same as in
турками там с иранцами это так же как в
our country. If we take the Ukrainians, yes, there is
нас Если мы возьмем украинцы да
a part that was closer to Russia, there is
то часть и которая была ближе к России
a part that is closer to Poland, where
часть где ближе к Польше где до
they are to Hungary  they speak a little differently
Венгрии они по-разному немного говорят
and that's normal, yes, we have the same thing here,
И это нормально так у нас у нас то же самое
because of course Who are you? You hear a lot, you
потому что Конечно Кто ты много Слышишь ты
will take something from them, it's the
будет взять из них
same with us, for example, someone on the
что-то у нас то же самое например кто-то на
border with Kurds, Turks, they talk to
границу с курдам туркам они разговаривают
tourists, some to Arabs, but that's good  for the
туристки кто из арабов но это хорошо для
Kurds, they speak a lot of
курдов они говорят очень много
different languages. Well, for example, all
разных языков Ну например прямо всех
Kurds know at least three languages, at least
курдов знают минимум три языка минимум
one, then the country in which they live, or
такую ​​потом страну в которой живет или там
Turkish or Arabic and English. Yes,
турецкий или арабский и английский Да
they speak English.
английский нуть Они тоже так это просто
for example, do you
вот маски получается потом еще например
want to learn another language or are you
хочешь учить что-то другой язык или тебя
interested in something else, but just to
интересует что-то другое но на просто на
start as a native language, there are at least three
начинаться как родной язык есть минимум три есть
people, for example, they teach Arabic and
люди например учат арабский и
Persian too Well, I am very
персидский тоже Ну мне вообще очень С
interested in talking with you I am not from Israel I am
тобой интересно поговорить Я не из Израиля Я
from Ukraine This is me today, just me
из Украины Это я сегодня просто я на
I hang different flags on different streams and
разные стримы вешаю разные флаги и
watch how people from different countries react,
смотрю как люди из разных стран реагируют
and I was also interested in how people
да и мне интересно было как на люди на
would react to the Israeli flag,
флаг Израиля да будут реагировать назад
because there, in Germany, some Russian woman is
что там вот в Германии какая-нибудь россиянка
aggressive  I was, yes, before that, you are quite
агрессивна была да до этого ты достаточно
normal, yes, you behave absolutely, and I myself am
нормально да абсолютно относишься и я сам
from Ukraine, I am from Ukraine, from the city of
из Украины Я из Украины из города
Khmelnytskyi, yes, I have such an entourage,
Хмельницкого да это у меня такой Антураж
I am not very similar to Israelis.
я не очень похож на израильтяне на что-то
I hear Ukrainian words coming out of you
общаться и слышу у тебя проскакивают
and I'm like wow and you know
украинские слова и я такой вау и знаешь
what I want to say that in my country there are a
что я хочу сказать что ее в моей стране
lot of 30-year-old people who speak Ukrainian, it's
очень многие 30 лет говорят
hard for me to learn Ukrainian I'm
во мне мне тяжело выучить украинский Я
used to it  in Russian Yes, you are a person from a
привык українською Да ты человек какой из
completely different country Yes, who during the three
совершенно другой страны Да которая за три
years of living in Ukraine
годы жизни в Украине
studied and learned the language at such a
ее училась и выучила язык на таком
level that you can calmly communicate
уровни что ты можешь спокойно общаться
not just on the topic Give me bread
не просто на тему Дайте мне хлеб
Take money so you can communicate
Возьмите деньги так ты можешь общаться
about some history, politics yes  And when
о какой-то истории политике да И когда
people in my country speak to me
люди в моей стране некоторые говорят мне
in a difficult way, they speak Ukrainian, my
тяжело говорить по-украински у меня
jaw is not like that Well, it's funny, it's
челюсть не такая Ну это смешно это
actually very, very cool.
на самом деле очень классно Ты ты
cool cat Yes, and such a
классного Да и такого
cat, they are beautiful, beautiful, yes Well,
котика они они хорошие красивые да Ну в
I also had a very, very interesting
меня тоже было очень очень такое интересно
conversation, it was very
разговор очень было что очень много
informative
информации А вас смотри флаг
yes, now the flag of Iraqi
принципе так сейчас флаг иракский
Kurdistan is a little more popular for the
курдистан Немножко более популярен для
name of the Kurds, for example, who sees this
имя курдов например кто видит этот
flag, they know, for example, it is the flag of
флаг Они знают например это флаг
Kurdistan, but because
курдистан а потому что
the other, the other, it can be like
другая Другая может
that, the sun, red, white,
это да солнце красный белый
and well, it's more  it's popular because it's
А ну это более популярно потому что это
official eyelashes, not the Internet, someone will
официальные ресницы не интернет кто-то будет
have written Kurdistan, it will be, but this one, for
написал курдистан это будет но этот
example, is not a flag in Turkey, it's not
например флег в Турции это не это не
allowed, for example. Well, it's forbidden, yes,
льзя например Ну да он запрещен да
Uhu. If you walk on this flag like that, life
Угу Если так ходишь на этот флаг жизни
will end.
закончится
Thank you very much for this
давай тебе большое большое спасибо за эту
conversation. Have a
разговор
very nice evening. Thank you very much.  let's get
тебе очень хорошего вечера Очень Спасибо
it together, let's take it off, I'll
похожий попереше кипаца сладите я
take it off, I
сниму да
promise everyone who
договорю все кто нас
watches us, if you still haven't switched to the
смотрите если вы до сих пор не перешли на
Ukrainian language
украинский язык
after almost 3 years of war, you're
за почти годы войны
already a man, Kurt from Turkey, lived in Kyiv for
уже человек Курт из Турции жил в Киеве
3 years, studied to be a programmer,
3 по года учился на программиста на
applied
прикладную
mathematics,
математику
learned the Ukrainian
выучил украинский
language, so what about the accent, yes  It can be seen that
язык Так что ну акцент да Видно что акцент
there is some accent, I blurt out the words, but they speak
некоторый там слова проскальзываю а говорят
absolutely normally, and you are still shy. And what will
абсолютно Нормально а вы до сих пор стесняетесь
people think?
А что люди подумают А у меня суржик А в
centuries or millennia or Russian
лет веков тысячелетий или русских
bombs and rockets so that you switch to
бомб и ракет чтобы вы перешли на
Ukrainian in everyday
украинский язык в повседневной
communication so that you and your children
общении чтобы вы со своими детьми
communicate in Ukrainian so that you
общались на украинском чтобы вы
come to a store in Ukraine and buy
приходили в Украину в магазин и покупали
these goods and communicate with the
е этот товары и общались с
Ukrainian saleswoman and the sellers
продавщицей на украинском и продавцы чтобы с
communicate with you in Ukrainian so that
вами общались на украинском чтобы
they listened to Ukrainian music more, and so
музыку украинскую больше слушали и так
on, yes, and that is, the Ukrainian language. It should
далее да и то есть украинский язык
be everywhere, it’s not like that. You know, it’s the language of
быть повсюду это не так что Знаете это язык
someone there, only when the news
каких-то там только когда по телку новости
is shown on TV, and who  when he says some excuses
показывают и кто когда говорит какие-то отмазки
that I'm already so used to it, it's damn hard for me to
что я уже так привык Мне тяжело
switch to the Ukrainian language,
Блин перейти на украинский язык
in fact, it's a matter of
на самом деле это вопрос
one, two or three months, it's actually not
одного-трех месяцев это на самом деле
even a matter of a month, it's a matter of
даже вопрос не месяц этот вопрос
internal desire. I switched to
внутреннего желания Я перешел на
Ukrainian completely when I was somewhere in the
украинский полностью в когда был где-то на
second course, when he contacted  with
курсе второго когда я связался с
good nationalists. It was cool,
националистами хорошими Это было классно
yes, because before that I lived in the city, I
да потому что до того я жил в городе у меня
have grandparents, yes, they are
получается бабушка дедушка да они
Ukrainian-speaking, my father was in People's Russia,
украиноязычный отец в народном Руси был
yes, this one  everything was great, but I was surrounded. The school
да е-е этот супер все но окружил Школа
I had under the Union was Russian-speaking, and
была при Союзе у меня русскоязычная да
then when the Union collapsed, it
е уже потом меня при как Союз рухнул да
turned out that there were already Ukrainian-speaking ones,
получилось в украиноязычные типа уже были
but still, most of the guys in the yard, all
но все равно большинство во дворе все
the girls, already spoke Russian.
парни Девушки говорили уже на русском
And everywhere, everything was from Russian, and
Но всюду все это было с русской и
I  in principle, until the 11th grade, yes, I was
я в принципе до 11-го класса да был
more Russian-speaking, you can say Yes,
больше русскоязычный можно сказать
yes, I was for Ukraine Yes, my father was
да е я был за Украину Да у меня папа был
in People's Russia, he was
в народном Руси Он когда этот развалили
there when the Soviet Union collapsed and  The KGB
Советский Союз там и КГБ против него
was there against him and all kinds of things. Yes, but
было там и всякие всякие штуки Да но вот
we were growing up, but
мы росли но
I was in the second year, somewhere in 2000,
был Я на курсе втором где-то это где-то 2000
2001, 2001, in my opinion, it
2001 год 2001 год по-моему это уже
was already in contact with good people. Yes,
было связалось с хорошими людьми Да
and I decided to switch completely to
и принял решение перейти полностью на
Ukrainian.  it was
украинский первые месяцы это Немножко было
strange because it popped up all the same
потому что оно выскакивало все равно
Russian popped up and then once and
русские выскакивалось а затем раз и
it went like a mass And now now I
пошло как по массу А сейчас сейчас я некоторые
speak like
говор говорить
this  Damn, how will it be in Russian,
такой Блин как это будет на русском языке
because when they say no, I’m already like, I
да потому что когда говорят нет я типа уже Я
think in Russian, my jaw is already shorter there,
думаю українською у меня уже короче там
the Russian-speaking jaw is formed, it’s
челюсть сформировалась русскоязычная это
all [ __ ], you think in Russian
все фигня вы думаете українською потому
because you only speak Russian every day,
что вы каждый день только и говорите
if you
українською Если вы будете повседневно
speaks Ukrainian every day, yes, you will
говорить по-украински да вы будете
think normally in Ukrainian, yes, and that's all.
нормально думать на украинском да и все
That's why
Поэтому
I think this video will definitely become
Я думаю этот ролик это обязательно получится
a video. It's
видео Это я
just me. It's the pearl of today's stream.
просто это Жемчужина сегодняшнего стрима
I'll post it separately on YouTube so that
я отдельно выложу его на YouTube чтобы
everyone is a Russian-speaking Ukrainian. Yes,
каждый этот русскоязычный украинец Да
if you
какой
look, a Ukrainian is sitting under an
посмотрит сидящий украинец под
Israeli flag, talking to a Kurd
израильским флагом говорит с курдом
who will learn Ukrainian. Damn, this is
который выучу украинский Блин это качество
some kind of brain explosion, not a word of mouth, and it’s
какой-то взрыв мозга а не осознанно и это
called narosno, no, you ca
называется нарошно не ну так как этот
n’t come up with this one on purpose, and everyone who has
намеренно не придумаешь и чтобы каждый кто
n’t switched to Ukrainian yet is
до сих пор не перешел на украинский
ashamed and hesitates  is lazy and so
стесняется колеблется ленится и так
on, so that he
дальше чтобы у него
feels like
окнуло вот здесь в
his heart and
начал стучать в его сердце и
do Ukrainian because it's cool.
делайте украинский потому что это классно
Glory to Ukraine, like, subscribe, comment and
Слава Украине лайк подписка коммент и
share this video with your friends, subscribe to
распространите этот вид друзьям подпишись на
my Telegram right now. Here he is,
мой Telegram прям сейчас Вот он апопик
it's very, very important. YouTube drives
это очень и очень важно YouTube загоняет
us to a shadow ban because of complaints from Orks, and
нас через жалобыорков в теневой бан и
a lot of videos are not shown to people
очень много видео не показываются людям
on time.  information about
вовремя не показывается информация о
the streams is displayed, so that we can have an
потому что для того чтобы мы имели
operational connection, subscribe right
оперативная связь подпишитесь прямо
now. And Popyk, in addition to
сейчас А Попик там в телеграмме кроме
videos, there is also interesting and useful
видео еще есть интересная и полезная
information in Telegram  and we must keep in
информация и мы должны с вами держать
constant operational contact with you Regardless
постоянная оперативная связь Независимо
of whether YouTube will show you about it
от того покажет ли вам об этом YouTube
Glory to Ukraine subscribe
Слава Украине подпишись